"Be the change you want to see in the world."

# Türker Emre AKGÜL

Cengiz Topel Caddesi, No:18/8, Bahçelievler - ISTANBUL Phone: 0533 641 6186

E-Mail: turkerea@gmail.com

# **COVER LETTER**

Regarding my 8 years experience in advertising & marketing, I would like you to evaluate my resume below for a career possibility in this beautiful country of yours Endonesia. I do believe that I can create difference in marketing, advertising and social media fields with my esoteric and out-of-box approach.

Currently I have been working as the Country Manager of a reputable Germany based sports marketing agency in Istanbul but I do need a drastic change in my life and after spending a month in Bali/Jakarta I believe I have found the change I need. I do want to live in either Bali or Jakarta and ready to do/give up anyhing to reach this goal.

My bilingual writing skills and my creative mind has always opened extraordinary paths for me so I believe they will help me out on this new career journey of mine too!

Best Regards.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **RESULT SPORTS TÜRKİYE**

www.resultsports-tr.com

# **Country Manager/Country Partner (2015 - Current)**

- Managing the whole operations in Turkish sports scene from football, basketball, volleyball and motors sports.
- Hiring/Educating new staff.
- Leading the creative team for digital projects.
- Assisting to the Germany office with their montly content
- Creating targets/goals of sales and business development teams.

# **REKMOB\***

www.rekmob.com

# **Business Development Director (2015)**

- Developing sales strategies for the ad areas of the mobile apps that the company has.
- Monetizing the ad fields of the mobile apps.
- Enlarging the mobile app inventory.
- Creating new and high-tech ad areas on mobile apps.

<sup>\*</sup>This startup company got bought by a large venture company in Turkey, following the success we created. Please Google it for more info.

### Mr. LAMA STUDIOS

www.mrlama.com

# Senior Project Manager (2014-2015)

- Establishing strategic plans to achieve maximum profits, and expanding customer database through extensive marketing and providing excellent customer support.
- Developing advertising sales strategies to drive an effective revenue.
- Sales of current services such as consultancy, mobile projects, games and animation.
- Planning, executing and managing key projects of brands like Pepsi, Akbank, Kanyon,n11.com, L'oréal, Turkcell, Avea, Vodafone.
- Planning periodic key brand visits.
- Maximizing productivity and creating a healthy environment for the team.
- Creating new business pitches and preparing presentations for international clients and suppliers from several countries such as Spain, Ireland, Philippines.
- Preparing sales quotes and client contracts.
- Troubleshooting.

# AROX INFORMATION SYSTEMS

www.arox.net

**Mobile Marketing Manager (2014)** 

• Achieving sales of mobile ads for over 80 applications that provides service to industries like Telco, Finance, FMCG and much more.

- Creating new business pitches for mobile advertising inventory.
- Growing and developing existing clients, together with generating new business activities.
- Devising marketing strategies -both conventional and guerrilla- to drive traffic to mobile applications.
- Planning periodic brand/agency visits for cultivating and growing client relationships.
- Ensuring the management of relationships with business partners (Ad Sale Houses, Media Agencies)
- Building partnerships and coordinating revenue share payments to business partners.
- Networking nationally, regionally, and locally to stay abreast of emerging advertising trends, rates and product solutions.
- Creating content marketing strategies for owned, earned and paid media.
- Organizing online and offline PR strategies with the support of PR team.

### AROX INFORMATION SYSTEMS

www.arox.net

# **Content Manager** (2013 –2014)

- Supervising Social Media and Account Management teams
- Keeping mobile apps (over 80) fed and developed with brand new content in regular periods.
- Creating new mobile application ideas and strategies in order to enlarge the

inventory.

- Mapping out the content strategy of the company.
- Consulting with company officials and coordinating with the sales department members for appealing promotional plans of the agency.

# **TT REKLAM WEB**

www.ttreklamweb.com

# **Key Account Manager (2012-2013)**

• Meeting and liaising with clients to discuss and identify their advertising

requirements.

- Presenting campaign ideas and costings to the clients.
- Briefing the creative and production teams which will prepare the adverts.
- Negotiating with clients, solving problems and making sure that expected deadlines are met.
- Keeping in contact with the client at all stages of the campaign.
- Managing the account's budget and invoicing the client
- Making pitches to win new business.

### TT REKLAM WEB

www.ttreklamweb.com

### Senior Copywriter (2008-2011)

- Creating original copies that transmit the core message of the brand.
- Creating advertising concepts for both local and international brands.
- Creating campaign contents
- Leading the creative process from beginning to end.
- Supervising Junior Copywriters.

# **TT REKLAM WEB**

www.ttreklamweb.com

# Jr. Copywriter (2006 - 2008)

- Creating original copies that transmit the core message of the brand.
- Developing creative ideas and preparing PowerPoint presentations.
- Proofreading copies to check spelling and grammar both in English and Turkish.
- Keeping the whole team up with popular culture and marketing trends.
- Translation from Turkish to English and vise-versa.

# **BRANDS & COMPANIES & PROJECTS**

### • Turkcell, AVEA, Vodafone

Conceptualizing and selling next-gen marketing tools as an official partner.

#### Akbank

Mentoring and consulting marketing department in mobile projects.

#### Kanyon

Mentoring and consulting marketing department in mobile & digital projects.

Sales of digital ideas.

#### ASUS

Leading Social Media operations, advergames & events

#### Martı Group

Creating concepts of all the group hotels & marinas.

#### • TEMA Foundation

Creating first social media communication through Facebook. Creating local, nationwide and international campaigns.

#### • Sakıp Sabancı Museum

Creating copies for the art pieces to provide a better experience for the visitors.

#### BAT

Sales of various digital projects such as mobile applications, mobile games.

#### Vakıf Emeklilik

Sales of various digital projects such as mobile applications.

#### • Rep. of Turkey Culture and Tourism Ministry

Writing and supervising the scripts of animation movies.

#### MEY

Sales of various digital projects such as mobile applications.

#### Vitra

Sales of various digital projects such as mobile applications.

### ◆Topkapı Museum

Providing original content for the art pieces.

### **SKILLS**

- Extensive knowledge of both online and offline advertising ecosystem.
- Strong content and concept creation abilities for online & offline platforms such as mobile applications, advergames, websites.
- Five years of experience as a senior digital advertising sales role with proven success of driving revenue and achieving digital advertising sales targets.
- Demonstrated successful history of establishing and maintaining B2B & B2C accounts and sales.
- Understanding mobile behavior, user consumption and buying habits.
- Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint.
- A dynamic personality and excellent presentation skills.
- Problem-solving and decision-making skills as a strong team player.

### **EDUCATION**

- Abant İzzet Baysal University Sports Academy 2003
- İstanbul University Sociology 2008

### **LANGUAGES**

- **English** (Proficient Level)
- Spanish (Beginning Level)
- **Turkish** (Native)

### **INTEREST**

- Photography
- Writing
- Reading
- Music
- Movies
- Playing Guitar
- Video Games

### **REFERENCES**

Sait Oksuz (Former Employer)

0212 263 4636

Co-Founder, General Manager, **Arox Information Systems**Letter of recommendation can be obtained.

### Sibel Şahin (Former Director)

0530 143 0755

Marketing & Sales Director, **Arox Information Systems**Letter of recommendation can be obtained.

# Gülü BAHADIR (Former Employer)

0532 456 96 60

Agency Owner, Creative Director, **TT Reklam Web** Letter of recommendation can be obtained.